ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/102 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Chaikin (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Includes: Chaikin at Democratic National Convention, 1980; Pres. Chaikin admires AFL-CIO's George Meany Human Rights Award presented to chief Mongosuthu Gatsha Buthelezi; 10/28/82; Woman working in garment shop, Johannesburg, South Africa, Dec. 1982; ILGWU Pres. Sol C. Chaikin chairs a meeting of the AFL-CIO's Committee on Social Security, with AFL-CIO Social Security Director Bert Seidman and AFL-CIO Pres. Lane Kirkland, March 1983; Chaikin at meeting, May 1983
- Civil Rights (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Includes: Negro Labor Conference at Hotel Theresa in New York City, with speakers James B Carey-sect to CIO, Charles S. Zimmerman - VP ILG, and Lewis G. Himes - Representative of the AF of L, 3/11/52; Garment workers pause for one hour to pay respects to the late Martin Luther King and listen to the funeral services in Atlanta, New York City, 4/9/68; New York ILGers (predominantly black) on a prayer pilgrimage to Washington on May 17, 1957 to mark the anniversary of the Supreme Court decision that segregated schools are unconstitutional; Martin Luther King delivering a speech at unidentified location, no date; Martin Luther King, Jr. an aide to King, Michael Quill - President of Transportation Workers Union, and ILG President David Dubinsky - Secretary-Treasurer of the committee at a meeting of the AFL-CIO Trade Union Committee on Civil Rights, 1963; ILG members march on picket lines to protest segregation at stores in Southern Cities (Woolworth), New York City, April 1963; Two black men during march on Washington "For Jobs and Freedom", 8/28/63; Crowd of ILGers at Pennsylvania Station awaiting trip to Washington DC during march on Washington, New York, 8/28/63; ILG women in front of Washington Monument during the march on Washington, 8/28/63; View of the mall in front of the Capitol of thousand's awaiting Martin Luther King's speech, Washington DC, 8/28/63; Two ILGers read a copy of Justice during the trip to Washington DC, 8/28/63; Black female ILGer reads a copy of Justice during trip to Washington DC, 8/28/63; Two black female ILGers during march on Washington "for Jobs and Freedom", Washington DC 8/28/63
- Commercials (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Includes: 13 slides, no date
- Convention (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Includes: Speaker at ILGWU Golden Jubilee Convention, 1950; contact sheet from convention, no date
- Convention, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Includes: Mary Bartchok, President of Local 264 and Chairlady of Shuwall Dr. Pottstown, April 15 and 16, 1939
- Convention, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Includes: contact sheets from Convention 1983
- Convention Photos [folder 1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Convention Photos [folder 2 of 2], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Outwear Negotiations May 1979 (JUSTICE), Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Agreements and Negotiations/Outerwear 1976 Pacts and Negotiations, Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Central States, Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 1, Folder 26)
- AFL-CIO Convention - Oct. 1-5/Union Label Convention Sept. 28, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Includes: contact sheets for AFL-CIO Convention and Union Label Convention, 10/1/83 - 10/5/83
- Convention Photos [folder 1 of 2], 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes: Two women, June 1986; ILGWU members showing support for striking CWA workers, June 1986; man and woman speaking into microphone, June 1986; Female representative from Local 26, June 1986; Female representative from Puerto Rico, June 1986; Unidentified male delegate June 1986; Convention room full of delegates from the Locals, June 1986; A skit, June 1986; Numerous delegates filing into their positions, June 1986; Convention delegates holding hands, June 1986; Man and woman shaking hands at convention, June 1986; Female delegate, June 1986; table of delegates from various locals,, June 1986; Female delegate at microphone, June 1986; Delegates applaud, June 1986 (3 copies); Delegates applaud, June 1986; Delegates speak with a police officer, June 1986; Delegates speak at microphone, June 1986; Female delegate speaks at microphone, June 1986; Male representative, June 1986; Chaikin receives award at Grand Hyatt New York, no date; Jay Mazur at meeting, no date; Group photo of various ILG delegates, no date; Women reading a script, June 1986; Group of women being filmed, June 1986; Individual woman being filmed, 1986; Group of women being filmed, June 1986; Female delegates from Puerto Rico, June 1986; Women speaking, June 1986
- Convention Photos [folder 2 of 2], 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes: Chaikin delivering a speech, June 1986; Black woman being filmed, June 1986; Women with make-up artist, June 1986; Women reading a script, June 1986; Three women with scripts, June 1986; ILG members march to support striking CWA workers, June 1986; Four women being filmed, June 1986; Sketching on wood blocks, June 1986; Union label, no date; Women speaking into microphone, June 1986; Black woman speaking, June 1986; Five women, June 1986; Women at convention, June 1986; Convention delegates applaud, June 1986; Delegates seated at convention, June 1986; Asian delegate, June 1986; ILGWU chorus, June 1986; An ILGWU quilt, June 1986; Black delegate speaks at microphone, June 1986; Delegates voting, June 1986; Three men, June 1986; Female delegates, June 1986; ILGWU members, June 1986; ILGWU rally, June 1986; Jesse Jackson at convention, June 1986; Three black CWA strikers, June 1986; CWA striker, June 1986; Three black CWA strikers, June 1986; Hartford workers on strike, June 1986; Jesse Jackson speaking at CWA, June 1986; Two black women performing, June 1986; people at a meeting, June 1986; convention delegate asks a question, June 1986; ILGWU member with sign supporting CWA workers, June 1986; Rally against imports, June 1986
- Convention [folder 1 of 4], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Includes: Two women at convention, 1989; Jay Mazur and Edgar Romney at convention, 1989; Men at microphone, 1989; Gus Tyler delivering speech, 1989; Dr. Ruth Westheimer, 1989; Man delivering speech, 1989; Man delivering a speech, 1989; Three female ILGWU members, 1989; Female delegate, 1989; Delegates at convention, 1989; Candid photo of female delegate, 1989; Two delegates, 1989; Delegate speaking at microphone, 1989; Three delegate give "thumbs up", 1989; Eight delegates in an office, 1989; Eight delegates in an office, 1989; Eight delegates in an office, 1989; Delegate speaking at microphone, 1989; Man with machine used by court stenographer, 1989; Delegate speaking at microphone, 1989; Woman at microphone, 1989; Woman speaking at microphone, 1989
- Convention [folder 2 of 4], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Includes: Woman at microphone, 1989; Woman at microphone, 1989; Woman at microphone, 1989; Man with UMWA speaking at microphone, 1989; Speaker at convention, 1989; Candid photo of delegates, 1989; Two delegates at convention, 1989; Delegate using machine used by court stenographer, 1989; Candid photo of delegates, 1989; Candid photo of delegates, 1989; Speaker at delegation; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Jay Mazur, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Female delegates at microphone, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Candid photo of delegates, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Delegates at lunch, 1989; Delegates holding hands, 1989; Speaker at convention, 1989; Delegates holding hands, 1989; Female delegate, 1989; Delegate at lunch, 1989; Photos of black man, 1989; Woman giving "thumbs up", 1989
- Convention [folder 3 of 4], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Includes: Woman outside, 1989; Delegate with tape recorder; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Delegates receiving certificate of appreciation, 1989; Gerald Roy speaking to convention, 1989; Delegates in small meeting, 1989; Female delegate listening to tape player, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Female delegate with flowers and Jay Mazur, 1989; 6 delegates receive certificate of appreciation, 1989; Female delegate receives certificate of appreciation from Jay Mazur, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Delegate at microphone, 1989; Candid photo of delegate at convention, 1989; Candid photo of delegate at convention, 1989; Speaker art convention, 1989; Jay Mazur with convention staff member, 1989; Three convention staff members, 1989
- Convention [folder 4 of 4], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Includes: Delegate at microphone, 1989; Black delegate at microphone, 1989; Delegates in small meeting, 1989; Delegates applauding an unidentified man, 1989; Edger Romney speaking, 1989; Al Gore speaking, 1989; Jay Mazur holding a Garment Workers T-shirt, 1989; Dr. Ruth Westheimer, 1989; Jay Mazur speaking, 1989; Delegates with translating machine, 1989; Various delegates at table, 1989; Candid photo of delegate, 1989; Delegate reading ILGWU materials, 1989
- Convention (37) [folder 1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Includes: Contact sheets from convention, 1980?
- Convention (37) [folder 2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Daycare (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Includes: Pres. Sol C. Chaikin addresses opening ceremonies of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; General Secretary-Treasurer Jay Mazur speaks at opening of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Matilda Cuomo, wife of the governor speaks at opening of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; New York Mayor Ed Koch speaks at opening of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Local 23-25 manager Edgar Romney speaks at opening of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Harold Siegel, executive director of the Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, speaks at opening of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Children at Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Children at Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Sign outside of Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown, 11/7/84; Child graduates from Chinatown Daycare Center, 7/12/85; Children straighten caps during graduation from Chinatown Daycare Center, 7/12/85; Mother with child graduating from Chinatown Daycare Center, 7/12/85; Children in Chinatown Daycare Center, no date; Thanksgiving feast for children at Chinatown Daycare Center, Dec. 1984; Child wears firemen's "turn-out" suits at ILG/Sesame Street Program, 12/7/85; Children at Chinatown Daycare Center, no date; Teacher at Chinatown Daycare Center, Apr. 1986; Children with a fireman and his hat at Chinatown Daycare Center, Apr. 1986; Children and teachers at Chinatown Daycare Center, Apr. 1986; Contact sheets and negatives from Chinatown Daycare Center, no date -
- Daycare, Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Daycare, Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Demonstrations (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Includes: Robert Mickus, manager of Slate Belt Apparel Contractors' Association, Inc., his wife Marianne and their son, Robert Lewis Mickus, picket the entrance to offices of ILGWU in New York, 4/2/59; Two ILGWU passing out cards to drivers, July 1979; ILGers protest anti-union practices of JP Stevens at ITT, 12/1/80; four Asian women advertise a rally for ILGWU Local 23-25, 6/24/82; Contact sheets of strikers, no date; San Francisco ILGers demonstrate at Gunne Sax Facility, July-Aug. 1985; ILGWU demonstration, no date; ILGWU demonstration, no date; ILGWU rally, 1950's
- Demonstrations (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Includes: ILGers strike against Continental Eastern, Mar. 1990; ILG Executive VP Edgar Romney speaks to ILGers on strike against Domsey Trading, Mar. 1990
- Demonstrations (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Includes: ILGers demonstrate with other unions and community groups in Los Angeles, protesting manufacturer' attempts to import guest workers into the garment industry, Nov. 1987; ILGer from Local 23-25 makes a sign for picketing, no date; Edgar Romney and Jay Mazur at a meeting, no date; ILG member protest the minimum wage, Nov. 1987; Asian woman, no date; Man speaks at a meeting, no date
- Dubinsky (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Includes (no photos): Documentation of the dedication of the David Dubinsky Student Center at the Fashion Institute of Technology, 10/22/75, New York; Dubinsky biographical information, no date; Dubinsky, Raskin and Lazar Teper, no date; Dubinsky at microphone; Dubinsky with cigar, no date; Dubinsky biographical information; Dubinsky biographical information
- Lemlich, Clara [Shavelson] not in box (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Includes: Clara Lemlich as a young woman: she becomes a leader of the historic 1909 Shirtwaist Strike and was a founder of Local 25-- was not in box
- Dubinsky (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Includes (no photos): Dubinsky biographical information (4 copies), no date; Dubinsky biographical information, no date; Dubinsky biographical information, no date; Dubinsky biographical information, no date; Dubinsky biographical information, no date; Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the presidency of David Dubinsky and ILGWU Progress, Madison Square Garden, 6/13/57
- Dubrow, Evelyn (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Includes: VP Evelyn Dubrow - legislative directors, receives the Philip Hart Distinguished Consumer Service Award from the Consumer Federation of America from Esther Peterson, former special assistant for consumer affairs to President Carter, 7/7/81
- Eastern Region (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Includes: Joint negotiating teams from Maiden form Brassiere Co. discuss terms of renewal pact, includes Leon Milman - manager of Plainfield Local 149, VP Edward Kramer - Eastern Region general manager Peter Capitano, 3/31/60; Ed Banyai, manager at Suffolk County Local 107, examines targets for organizing drive on Long Island with VP Edward Kramer, general manager of Eastern Region, 10/15/61; Members of Local 222 protest the runaway attempt of Newark (NJ) Knitgoods from Madison St. - outside theater of Broadway hit "Come Blow Your Horn,: whose star is Hal March, President and treasurer of company, New York, 7/1/61; Member Local 220-251 with Sadie Reich - Manager, and Civil Rights Petition Committee collected 2325 signatures, Newark, 10/15/63; Connie Woodruff, attending the ILGWU Training Institute, hands out leaflets ("Don't buy Rhoda Lee") to shoppers - she was a former secretary to Pete Detlefsen at Local 144, New York; Herald Square 3/15/63; Three women talking, no date; Sol Goldberg no date; Eastern Region strike outside Dale Dress, Long Island, NY, 3/1/65; Tabulating votes cast by members for candidates running for local posts, 3/15/65; Final tally of ballots, supervised by VP Edward Kramer - election committee chairman with observers from both slates, 3/15/65; Workers of the Lewel Manufacturing Co. were given turkeys at a special meeting to discuss tactics with General Organizer Walter DeYoung and Lou Gargallo - staff members at Local 166, 12/1/65; Local 166 ILGWU on strike from Lewella MFG Co., 11/10/66; Eastern Region Locals 148-162 picket at Sears Fashion Distribution Center, North Bergen, NJ, 3/1/67; Newly-appointed Eastern Region Field Supervisor Arthur Skolnick and Raymond Bramucci -recently elected mayor of Union City, New Jersey Locals 148-162, are congratulated by VP Edward Kramer - general manager of the region, with Joseph McGlone, and Marion Badolato, Locals 148-164 president and recording secretary, respectively, 10/15/67; Eastern Region negotiators headed by VP Edward Kramer hammered out terms for workers at Lily of France with Jules Sippen Local 156 manager, Sol Goldberg - region assistant general manager members of the shop committee and employer representatives, 2/1/68; Union staffers Juan Muniz, Hugh Harris, Monserrate Lapen, Marlerne McQueen and Virgil Bavarro distribute clothing and food to fire victims, 5/15/88; ILGWU member Marie Miller, Berenice Vauters, and her mother Ruby Thompson, select clothing for their children at Union's Fire Emergency Distribution Center, 5/15/68; Rosalind Bowers, who received vitally needed clothing and other items, thanks ILGWU representatives Hugh Harris - assistant manager of Locals 220 - 251, Connie Woodruff - CRD director, Virgil Bavarro - assistant manager Local s 144-166- 222; VP Hubert Humphrey with Governor Richard Hughes, VP Edward Kramer manager of the Eastern Region, and Connie Woodruff - director of Eastern Region's Community Relations Department, Newark, 9/1/68; Abe Ribicoff and Edward Kramer, 10/15/68; Governor Meyner, 10/15/69
- Eastern Region (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Includes: ILGers at hearing of the domestic finance subcommittee of the House Banking and Currency Committee on consumer needs and related matters, with Ray Bramucci - manager of Eastern Region Local 148-162, Mildred Lippman EOT Education Director, Connie Woodruff - Eastern Region community relations, and chairman of the subcommittee Congressman Wright Patman, Texas Democrat, Newark, 11/10/69; Senator Williams at a meeting, 6/1/70; Senator Williams with elderly woman, no date; Senator Williams with female workers, 6/1/70; VP Edward Kramer, general manager of the Eastern Region, wishes candidate Kenneth Gibson good luck in the runoff for Mayor of Newark, NJ, 6/1/70; VP Edward Kramer, general manager of the Eastern Region holds ILGWU constitution at swearing-in ceremony for new posts, with Saul Rosen, new associate manager of Mount Vernon Locals 137, 140 and 143, Sidney Schuster - new manager of Passaic Local 145, Hugh Harris assuming Schuster's spot as Newark Local 220-251 manager, Sol Goldberg - Eastern Region assistant general manager, and Richard Sanfilippo - leaving Passaic to become the region's field supervisor, 6/15/70; Strikers in front of Freund Knitting Mills, 10/1/70; ILGers of Eastern Region Locals 57 and 77 in Queens and Nassau Counties, led by Manager Richard Cerbone gather to greet Arthur J. Goldberg at a rally in Queens, 9/1/70; Over 100 Northern New Jersey ILGers gather at a statue of Cuban patriot Jose Marti in West New York to commemorate his birthday, with President Raymond Padrazza of Eastern Region Locals 148-162, and Business Agent George Benson of Locals 148-162, 2/15/71; Local 145 ILGers picket Norwood strikers spend Christmas season on Eastern Region's picketline, Northvale, NJ, 1/1/74; Dave Corbin, Ramon Lopez, and John Hogan picket Dover Industries led by Manager Schlesinger of Eastern Region Local 221 in Elizabeth, NJ, assisted by Business Agent John Finnegan, Whippany, NJ, 11/1/71; Strikers at Domestic Lace, Englewood, NJ 2/15/72; Local 145 members strike at Norwood Knitting Mills, 1/1/74; Democratic gubernatorial candidate Brenden Byrne and VP Edward Kramer - Eastern Region general manager speak to ILGers at Holly Stores, 9/24/73; Brenden Byrne labor-backed Democratic candidate for Governor of New Jersey discusses key issues at a Newark rally Oct. 27 for 400 chairladies, executive board members and active ILGers of Eastern Region and Cloak Out-of-Town Local in the state, 10/27/73; Eastern Region and EOT officials welcome gubernatorial candidate Brenden Byrne at Newark ILGWU headquarters, with VP Edward Kramer - Eastern Region general manager, Sol Goldberg - the region's field supervisor, 10/29/73; VP Joe Fisher manager of Philadelphia Knitgoods Local 190 who serves as Jewish Labor Committee (JLC) secretary and executive board member of JOINT VP Irwin Soloman - Eastern Pennsylvania Regional director who is JLC president and co-chairman of JOINT, James H. Jones president at the Negro Trade Union Leadership Council and JOINT co-chairman, and Michael Perry, JLC area director, Jul-Aug 1982
- Educational Department/Educational Department and Training Institute (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Includes: President Louis Stulberg opens meeting of the ILGWU National Scholarship Fund Selection Committee at the Hotel Warwick with Assistant President Gus Tyler, director of the Education Department and administrator of the fund, Dr. Robert Lincoln, education staffer Harriet Cohan, James Smothers Jr., Dr. William Kelly, Jasper Peyton - assistant education director, Rev. Miles L. Fay, S. J., Dr. Remigro U. Pane, Louis Nunez, Executive VP Wilbur Daniels, Dr. Philip Driscoll, Edwinna Hagstrom, and education staffer Kitty Murphy 4/23/71; Mural commemorating the 75th anniversary of the Ladies' Garment Workers' Union created with help at Jasper Payton ILGWU's education director, and curator Nina Felshin, no date; Students in the ILGWU Education Department's art class at the General Office with Xiomara Beata, Lucy Coher, an executive board member at Local 66, Diana Beata, Nelda Beata Local 40 member, and Lucy Rodriguez of the Local 40 Education Department, 3/1/75; Mural of 75 years of progress of ILGWU designed by Jasper Peyton, ILGWU assistant education director, 9/1/75; Mural of 75 years of progress of ILGWU designed by Jasper Peyton, ILGWU assistant education director, 9/1/75; ILGWU Assistant President Gus Tyler discussed classroom sessions and general aims of the program, 6/1/76; Copy of ILGWU film "With These Hands" presented to the seafarers' Harry Lundberg school in Piney Point, Maryland by ILGWU Assistant Education Director Jasper Peyton and former VP Charles S. Limmerman, with Hazel Brown, school president, and Mike Sacco, vice president, 5/15/77; Robert Fontaine instructs Staff Training Institute students in fine points of garment construction and piece rate negotiations, Jan 1986; ILG Art Class, n.d.
- Elections (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Includes: Votes are counted, Hazelton, Pennsylvania, April 1983; A ballot box is emptied for counting, New Bedford, Massachusetts, April 1983; Elections: the winners' names are posted, New Bedford, Massachusetts, April 1983; Local 600: members go to the polls, Puerto Rico, April 1983; Local 600: votes are tallied, Puerto Rico, April 1983; Dorothy Silvia, election and objection committee captain, observes as Office Manager Frances Cairns tallies the ballots on a candidate, New Bedford, Massachusetts, April 1983; Ohio District Council election tellers Peg Wells, Doris Blount, and Vicki Sue Thomas count ballots, April 1983; Chairperson Rose Andrejco casts her ballot as Delores Nuss at the election and objection committee looks on, Lewisburg, Pennsylvania, April 1983
- Fashion Show '85, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Includes: Contact sheet of Fashion Show '85
- Full Employment Action Council (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Includes: Workers construct building with Solar Power Capabilities, 2/11/80; Workers construct building with Solar Power Capabilities, 2/11/80; President Jimmy Carter at White House, no date President Jimmy Carter at White House with Chaikin, no date
- GEB Selected Pictures (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Includes: The March of Dimes of Westchester County, New York presented an award to the ILGWU for having the highest pledge amount of labor unions involved in fund raising for the organization, with Lower Hudson District Council Mgr. Michael Trinchi, New York State District Director Salvatore Giordina, march of Dimes Westchester Director Jeff Witt, no date; Miguel Machuca, Director of Org. is surrounded by eight recipients of back pay awards and fellow Somma Strikers, no date; GEB meets, Feb. 1985
- General Executive Board (Box 3, Folder 10)